<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Travis Emslander</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Travis Emslander</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 08:10:13 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://travis.emslander.co/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CSS Anchor</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230301-css-anchor/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 08:10:13 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230301-css-anchor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Chrome canary builds now have a new &amp;ldquo;anchor&amp;rdquo; concept for CSS positioning which should be in future versions of Chrome. There is also development on a polyfill. This is interesting because it can be quite complex and difficult to reliably get positioning of an element based on another element. &lt;a href="https://developer.chrome.com/blog/tether-elements-to-each-other-with-css-anchor-positioning/">This article announcing this new feature goes into details&lt;/a> on the current methodology and what the new anchor method is.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Wikenigma</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230222-wikenigma/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 08:08:33 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230222-wikenigma/</guid><description>&lt;p>We all know about Wikipedia, it attempts to catalog all of human knowledge. I became aware earlier this week of &lt;a href="https://wikenigma.org.uk/">Wikenigma&lt;/a>, which does the opposite and catalogs all that we DON&amp;rsquo;T yet know. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting browsing through.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Troubleshooting Cloudflare and Stripe</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230222-troubleshooting-cloudflare-and-stripe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 08:06:05 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230222-troubleshooting-cloudflare-and-stripe/</guid><description>&lt;p>Troy Hunt is the creator of Have I Been PWNED, a service we use at &lt;a href="https://fieldnation.com/">Field Nation&lt;/a> to block logins that use passwords that were exposed in known data breaches. He wrote &lt;a href="https://www.troyhunt.com/down-the-cloudflare-stripe-owasp-rabbit-hole-a-tale-of-6-rabbits-deep/">this blog posting about an issue he was having&lt;/a> related to his use of Stripe for customer billing as well as Cloudflare. It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting read that shows some good troubleshooting as well as some information on how Cloudflare&amp;rsquo;s OWASP rules work.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Datalog</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230215-datalog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:10:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230215-datalog/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently read this &lt;a href="https://blogit.michelin.io/an-introduction-to-datalog/">explainer on Datalog&lt;/a>. I&amp;rsquo;ve never actually heard of this alternate query language. It is pretty interesting, and a couple of the use cases seem like they&amp;rsquo;d be great ways to represent comment network questions we have. However, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t clear by the end of the article where this can be used, and it noted that there are often performance issues in application of it which made me instantly much less interseted.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NLP Hallucinations</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230215-nlp-hallucinations/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 08:01:05 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230215-nlp-hallucinations/</guid><description>&lt;p>Someone playing around with the Bing ChatGPT product &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/kliu128/status/1623472922374574080?t=67TaIGJCwylbxegbU3IZfQ&amp;amp;s=09">believes they uncovered some initial prompts/instructions the chatbot has in how it does every conversation&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s very odd to read through and it appears it revealed its codename is Sydney.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The super weird part is people point out this may not even be true. A known issue in natural language processing called &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hallucination_(artificial_intelligence)#In_natural_language_processing">hallucination&lt;/a> where the model will serve up factually incorrect answers stated confidently. So it&amp;rsquo;s not clear if the AI is generating this text because it&amp;rsquo;s in fact part of its ruleset that it got tricked in leaking, or if it&amp;rsquo;s generating it because it thinks it&amp;rsquo;s a good answer to the question (even if not true).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Pocket Guide to Debugging</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230208-pocket-guide-to-debugging/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230208-pocket-guide-to-debugging/</guid><description>&lt;p>I came across this funny little comic book about debugging called &lt;a href="https://wizardzines.com/zines/debugging-guide/">The Pocket Guide to Debugging&lt;/a> by Julia Evans. I thought this little book is great. It&amp;rsquo;s not only funny, but it&amp;rsquo;s actually really great advice on how to debug problems. It&amp;rsquo;s full of a lot of best practices I&amp;rsquo;ve used and coached people on over the years, as well as a few I&amp;rsquo;ll definitely start recommending.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Floating Point Numbers</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230125-floating-point-numbers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230125-floating-point-numbers/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not all engineers are aware, but floating points are attempts at representing a fraction in binary. They are often not able to be an exact representation of the number and are as close an approximation as can be achieved. This leads to lots of potential issues when doing math with floating points, as most of the engineers on the WOOP team who have tried summing our pay accounting table (also why we never should use floating points for financial purposes). I ran across &lt;a href="https://jvns.ca/blog/2023/01/13/examples-of-floating-point-problems/">this really nice writeup on various horror stories people have had come up with floating point numbers&lt;/a>. It&amp;rsquo;s a great read to learn from others mistakes and hopefully avoid some of these pitfalls yourself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ChatGPT Makes Terrible Errors</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230118-chatgpt-makes-terrible-errors/20230118-chatgpt-makes-terrible-errors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230118-chatgpt-makes-terrible-errors/20230118-chatgpt-makes-terrible-errors/</guid><description>&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot shared here and posted elsewhere on the internet about the amazing things large language model AI like ChatGPT can produce. I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share &lt;a href="https://mastodon.social/@nixCraft/109706956125065137">this funny post&lt;/a> as a helpful reminder that it makes terrible errors as well. It can be pretty funny, but this is where serious dangers exist for this technology as people may trust it as &amp;ldquo;all knowing&amp;rdquo; and take any answer it gives as truth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>ICANN DNS</title><link>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230104-icann-dns/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 08:39:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://travis.emslander.co/posts/20230104-icann-dns/</guid><description>&lt;p>I enjoy watching Marques Brownlee (MKBHD) on Youtube. He&amp;rsquo;s a tech youtuber who mostly reviews computers, phones, and other gadgets. Recently I started listening to a podcast he and his crew created called Waveform. On a recent episode they did a &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=26WvISI14g0">deep dive into DNS and ICANN&lt;/a> (you can find an audio version of their podcast too) that I found was really helpful to fill in the gaps of why DNS was created and some challenges it&amp;rsquo;s had and how it&amp;rsquo;s worked through it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>